today we're going to be reviewing the
ember smart mug and I warn you now this
review might induce a little bit of
outrage so why would this product or
this review make you a little bit angry
well let's start with a few things this
is a smart mug it connects to your phone
via bluetooth it costs pretty much 80
pounds one of the first things that I
did after getting this was connected to
my phone and update the firmware on my
coffee cup now all of those things do
make this seem completely ridiculous I'm
going to top it all I really like it
let's explain a little bit more about
what this does and why it does it and
why on earth I think that this is
actually quite a good product so the way
this mug works it is a smart mug it has
a battery in the base as well as an
element and a thermometer and you tell
it what temperature you want your coffee
to be you put your coffee in the cup and
it will cool to your desired temperature
it'll notify you that it's your desired
temperature and it will hold it at that
temperature
that seems a little bit ridiculous and I
can already hear you telling me how nice
it is when coffee cools down and you can
enjoy all the flavors all the more and
letting coffee cool is a good thing and
why would you want to heat it
don't thermos has already existed what
is wrong with me why would I spend 80
pounds of my own money on a coffee cup
like this those are all valid questions
and frankly I was a little skeptical of
this at the start I put out on Twitter
to see if anyone had one what their
experiences were and was somewhat
surprised when there was a universal
positive response to it
and at that point I had to pull the
trigger I had to buy one and I'll be
honest only one of these will mean that
your colleagues friends and loved ones
will mock you mercilessly for owning an
incredibly expensive smart mug that
holds coffee at a particular temperature
of your choosing so I'll give you the
moment where this went from being an
amusing knob
an excess of the internet-of-things to
being something that I was quite
grateful to have on my desk now this I
think this has a specific audience which
are people who often work at desks and
are easily distracted by stuff and
that's me I'll be honest I often work at
a desk not always but I am very easily
distracted by lots of different things
let me set the scene I said on my desk
someone came in and poured me a mug full
of filter coffee and it was a preview
roaster kind of a test development Roast
of a new coffee that was pretty excited
to taste and they wanted some feedback
on it and it was too hot to drink
I was working away and then I got called
out of where I was working to go and do
some other stuff and it took way longer
than I expected 10-15 minutes and I came
back and I sat down and I was a little
sad because I'd missed really that kind
of peak moment for for capturing
flavonoids where it's not hot but it's
certainly not cold and yet I reached
across grab my cup and there it was this
perfect temperature cup of coffee just
said waiting for me it had not
particularly degraded in the 10 or 15
minutes that I've been gone even though
it had been actively heated but it had
been very gently very lightly heated it
tasted great I really enjoyed it and I
had this moment of like wow I'm grateful
to own this now this is I know this is a
little absurd it's all a little absurd I
kind of get why people who buy these
come to really like them now if you're
someone who has the time and space and
energy and workflow in your life to to
brew a delicious cup of coffee to sit
down to focus on it capture it at it's
perfect moment in time and temperature
and enjoy it I envy you I am NOT that
person I live a life full of
distractions so it's all too easy for me
to miss my favorite moment and that's
kind of sad now this has sort of saved
that more than enough times in a week
for me to feel like this was a good idea
now this really is only gonna live on a
desk it's battery-powered right so the
way it works is it charges on this
little saucer type thing that has
plugged into a wall socket so I suspect
this doesn't live in people's houses
really I suspect this lives where people
work last I think a couple
hours depending on how hot you want your
coffee to stay there's a little chart
that they give you when you buy one of
these so uh you know I'm generally
trying to keep my coffee around the very
early 50s in terms of degrees Celsius I
can't do the other you know temperature
I'm just not into it I'm just not I'll
say it now III can't do Fahrenheit I
just can't do it so this it's 50 52 54
if I'm feeling like I need a little bit
more warmth in my coffee and and I get
it I get i get that you if you saw me
with this would want to tease me and you
should and that's okay you should
absolutely tease anyone who spent that
much money on one of these but they're
also having a kind of a good time with
it
it's hot it's you know it's I'm just
deeply I'm troubled by this I'm troubled
by it let's not say that this is a
flawless product let's talk through a
few issues that I have with this thing
and the most obvious one I think to just
about anyone aside from the price
because it is expensive is the way that
it charges now it's pretty simple there
is two rings here that meet two
contactors so it doesn't matter which
way around you have the mug you'd have
to have it in a certain position as long
as it's just on the base now this nature
of charging means that this is not
dishwasher safe now I'm sort of stunned
that they didn't go for cheap charging
or something like it and went for these
contactors because not making this
dishwasher safe seems like a massive
error people have put these through
dishwashers and they have survived it
will certainly be fine with a hand wash
it just seems like a weird design
decision second thing you actually lose
a reasonable amount of capacity in the
mug to the battery and the heating unit
so it looks like a decent sized mug but
it's actually quite a bit smaller on the
inside than you think it is capacity is
not a huge issue for me it's that moment
where I pick it up and I think I have
more coffee than I do and then I find I
don't and I'm sad I don't like to feel
sad over things as stupid is not having
enough coffee in my coffee cup so it
will trick you now and again into
thinking it's fuller than it is this
one's black so we look in the top that
doesn't really help
you either now finally this hasn't
happened to me I haven't had this long
enough but I have read that some people
possibly with earlier models had issues
with the inside coating flaking off as I
said that hasn't happened to me but it
is something I will be paying attention
to and worrying about inevitably there's
an app and the app is a little over
engineered I'm not gonna lie I do quite
like having a little notification up
here to tell me that my coffee is the
perfect temperature to drink and the
control wheel inside to choose my
temperature is very simple to use it
does offer you some more presets you can
do coffee consumption tracking I don't
care about any of that stuff and so here
we are
the ember mug it's ridiculous it's
ridiculous you're looking at this and
you're thinking that's ridiculous and
you're right but that doesn't mean I
can't like it or that you wouldn't like
it too is this the single best way you
can invest 80 pounds or in the u.s. $80
on your coffee experience no no it's
probably not does it meet the needs of
every person not even slightly but if
you like me often are distracted really
really love coffee and I kind of wanna
experience that kind of sweet spot for
as long as possible this is a solution
and I'm not sure there's a better
solution out there I have come to accept
the usefulness of thermoses is pretty
limited they keep things incredibly hot
to the point that that drives me kind of
insane when I've driven all the way to
the airport and I still can't drink my
coffee so maybe there's a middle ground
now they do a travel version of this
which is an intense amount of money it's
like a hundred and fifty pounds that is
way too much money I am NOT spending
that kind of money on a travel cup
that's just not happening but on this
little mug while I spent it now it's too
late I'm committed and maybe you know
that that's clouding my review but I had
been surprised and a little bit
delighted at the ridiculousness and the
wonderfulness of the Ember mug
if you have one of these I do want to
hear from you am I alone in this let me
know in the comments if you are watching
this and thinking this is the most
ridiculous thing you've ever heard
give it a thumbs up let me know let me
know if you have seen something similar
to this I want to see it I am curious
this this has surprised me and I felt I
had to talk about it as always thank you
so much for watching
[Music]
you